Tufts Published Scholarship PB
Tufts Archival Research Center
- Perseus Project Publications, 1987 -- 2014; PB.001; 56 Digital Object(s)
  - Collecting Fragmentary Authors in a Digital Library (Greek Fragmentary Historians), 2009; PB.001.010.00001; Berti, Monica; Romanello, Matteo; Babeu, Alison; Crane, Gregory
    This paper discusses new work to represent, in a digital library of classical sources, authors whose works themselves are lost and who survive only where surviving authors quote, paraphrase or allude to them. It describes initial works from a digital collection of such fragmentary authors designed not only to capture but to extend the ontologies that traditional scholarship has developed over generations: the aim is representing every nuance of print conventions while using the capabilities of digital libraries to extend our ability to identify fragments, to represent what we have identified, and to render the results of that work intellectually and physically more accessible than was possible in print culture.
    Digital libraries; XML (Document markup language); Fragmentary authors; Greek Fragmentary Historians; Text Encoding Initiative; Perseus Project
  - Improving OCR Accuracy for Classical Critical Editions, 2009; PB.001.011.00001; Boschetti, Federico; Romanello, Matteo; Babeu, Alison; Bamman, David; Crane, Gregory
    This paper describes a work-flow designed to populate a digital library of ancient Greek critical editions with highly accurate OCR scanned text. While the most recently available OCR engines are now able after suitable training to deal with the polytonic Greek fonts used in 19th and 20th century editions, further improvements can also be achieved with postprocessing. In particular, the progressive multiple alignment method applied to different OCR outputs based on the same images is discussed in this paper.
    Optical character recognition; Perseus Project
  - Rethinking Critical Editions of Fragmentary Texts By Ontologies, 2009; PB.001.012.00001; Romanello, Matteo; Boschetti, Federico; Berti, Monica; Babeu, Alison; Crane, Gregory
    This paper discusses the main issues encountered in the design of a domain ontology to represent ancient literary texts that survive only in fragments, i.e. through quotations embedded in other texts. The design approach presented in the paper combines a knowledge domain analysis conducted through semantic spaces with the integration of well established ontologies and the application of ontology design patterns. After briefly describing the specific meaning of "fragment" in a literary context, the paper gives insights into the main conceptual issues of the ontology design process. Lastly, it outlines the overall architecture of protocols, services and data repositories which is required to implement a digital edition of fragments based on the proposed ontology.
    Ontologies (Information retrieval); Perseus Project
  - When Printed Hypertexts Go Digital: Information Extraction from the Parsing of Indices, 2009; PB.001.012.00002; Romanello, Matteo; Berti, Monica; Babeu, Alison; Crane, Gregory
    Modern critical editions of ancient works generally include manually created indices of other sources quoted in the text. Since indices can be considered as a form of domain specific language, the paper presents a parsing-based approach to the problem of extracting information from them to support the creation of a collection of fragmentary texts. This paper first considers the characteristics and structure of quotation indices and their importance when dealing with fragmentary texts. It then presents the results of applying a fuzzy parser to the OCR transcription of an index of quotations to extract information from potentially noisy input.
    Hypertext systems; Indexes; Perseus Project
  - Technology and Greek in the Translation Course, 2014; PB.001.013.00001; Krohn, Anna.; Crane, Gregory.; The Greek or Latin literature in translation course is useful yet problematic. It offers a glimpse into the subject to entice first year students and to edify nonmajors. Instructors, however, are left with the task of attempting to contextualize and explain works to their Greekless and Latinless students without the aid of the original language to differentiate ideas. It is certainly possible to cover large concepts, such as _____. If, however, the word "anger" appears past the first line of the Iliad, how is a student to know if it represents _____ or something else which should impact their understanding the passage? Similarly, if given two different translations of the same text, how can a student judge the relative merit of those translations without knowledge of the original? In an academic environment where undergraduates are being encouraged to conduct original research earlier, educators can not simply provide translations minus understanding of the original language without robbing their students of vital information that could spur them on to further work. This paper documents a class wherein we attempted to bridge the gap between the translations and Greek texts. Our goal was not only to introduce our students to the works and the world where they originated but to also provoke critical thought and allow our students to engage directly with the original texts. Using a series of three projects, we demonstrated to the students how they could tackle and begin to understand an unfamiliar language via tools freely available on the internet. Based on our experiences teaching this class and reactions gathered from our students, we propose a new potential model for literature in translation courses.
    Greek language -- Computer assisted instruction.; Greek language -- Study and teaching.; Classical philology -- Study and teaching.; Tufts University. Department of Classics. Perseus Project
- Tufts Published Scholarship, 2008 -- 2014; 1983 -- 2014; PB.002; 26 Digital Object(s)
  This series contains scholarship published by Tufts faculty and staff.
  This series is arranged chronologically by accession.
  - Expanding the reach of health sciences education and empowering others: the OpenCourseWare initiative at Tufts University, 2008-01-01; PB.002.00001; Lee, Mary Y.; Albright, Susan; O'Leary, Lisa; Terkla, Dawn Geronimo; Wilson, Nancy
    OpenCourseWare (OCW) represents an innovative and cost-effective opportunity for institutions to take a more active role in strengthening health sciences education worldwide. OCW content can provide a supplement to curricula available in resource-rich settings, as well as provide much of the basic content critical to teaching and research in resource-limited health education environments. Educational institutions worldwide have the opportunity to explore how OCW and other open tools and materials can supplement efforts to build health education capacity to address global shortages of healthcare workers. Tufts University has worked to leverage open, digital resources to support medical education since 1994 with the creation of the Tufts University Sciences Knowledgebase (TUSK). This experience has yielded vital lessons for institutions interested in OCW, including: effectively motivating faculty participation; managing the inherent complexity of open publishing of health sciences content due to its rapidly evolving nature and reliance on copyrighted materials; generating support through internal and external communication throughout the process; and creating institutional systems that ensure the long-term sustainability of OCW initiatives.
    Internet in education; Distance education; Computer-assisted instruction; Tufts OpenCourseWare; Office of the Provost
  - Analytical modeling of degradation product partitioning kinetics in source zones containing entrapped DNAPL, 2011; PB.002.00002; Ramsburg, C. Andrew; Christ, John A.; Douglas, Scott R.; Boroumand, Ali
    Liquid-liquid equilibrium experiments indicate that there is a strong thermodynamic driving force for the reversible sequestration of cis-dichloroethene (DCE) within microbially active dense nonaqueous phase liquid (DNAPL) source zones containing chlorinated ethene solvents. Assessment of the importance of degradation product sequestration, however, requires accurate description of the mass transfer kinetics. Partitioning kinetics of cis-DCE were assessed in a series of transport experiments conducted in sandy columns containing uniformly entrapped tetrachloroethene (PCE)-nonaqueous phase liquids (NAPL). Effluent data from these experiments were simulated using an analytical solution adapted from the sorption literature. The solution permits interrogation of the relative importance of mass transfer resistance in the aqueous phase and NAPL. Column data and simulations suggest that the kinetic exchange of cis-DCE may be described with mass transfer correlations developed for the dissolution of pure component NAPLs. Diffusive transport within the entrapped ganglia was relatively fast, offering limited resistance to mass exchange. These results (1) establish the applicability of dissolution-based mass transfer correlations for modeling both absorption and dissolution of degradation products, (2) quantify the thermodynamic driving force for the partitioning of cis-DCE in PCE-NAPL by assessing the ternary phase behavior, and (3) guide incorporation and deployment of partitioning kinetics into multiphase compositional simulators when assessing or designing metabolic reductive dechlorination within DNAPL source zones. While focus is placed on examining degradation product partitioning in DNAPL source zones, results may also be useful when considering rate limitations in other liquid-liquid partitioning processes, such as partitioning tracer tests.
    Bioremediation; Groundwater--Quality; Department of Civil and Environmental Engineering
  - Evolution of a Major Drug Metabolizing Enzyme Defect in the Domestic Cat and Other Felidae: Phylogenetic Timing and the Role of Hypercarnivory, 2011; PB.002.00003; Court, Michael H.; Shrestha, Binu; Reed, J. Michael; Starks, Philip T.; Kaufman, Gretchen E.; Goldstone, Jared V.; O'Brien, Stephen J.; Koepfli, Klaus-Peter; Frank, Laurence G.; Roelke, Melody E.
    The domestic cat (Felis catus) shows remarkable sensitivity to the adverse effects of phenolic drugs, including acetaminophen and aspirin, as well as structurally-related toxicants found in the diet and environment. This idiosyncrasy results from pseudogenization of the gene encoding UDP-glucuronosyltransferase (UGT) 1A6, the major species-conserved phenol detoxification enzyme. Here, we established the phylogenetic timing of disruptive UGT1A6 mutations and explored the hypothesis that gene inactivation in cats was enabled by minimal exposure to plant-derived toxicants. Fixation of the UGT1A6 pseudogene was estimated to have occurred between 35 and 11 million years ago with all extant Felidae having dysfunctional UGT1A6. Out of 22 additional taxa sampled, representative of most Carnivora families, only brown hyena (Parahyaena brunnea) and northern elephant seal (Mirounga angustirostris) showed inactivating UGT1A6 mutations. A comprehensive literature review of the natural diet of the sampled taxa indicated that all species with defective UGT1A6 were hypercarnivores (>70% dietary animal matter). Furthermore those species with UGT1A6 defects showed evidence for reduced amino acid constraint (increased dN/dS ratios approaching the neutral selection value of 1.0) as compared with species with intact UGT1A6. In contrast, there was no evidence for reduced amino acid constraint for these same species within UGT1A1, the gene encoding the enzyme responsible for detoxification of endogenously generated bilirubin. Our results provide the first evidence suggesting that diet may have played a permissive role in the devolution of a mammalian drug metabolizing enzyme. Further work is needed to establish whether these preliminary findings can be generalized to all Carnivora.
    Drug tolerance; Phenols; Carnivora; Department of Molecular Physiology and Pharmacology
  - Multiresolution Decomposition Schemes Using the Parameterized Logarithmic Image Processing Model with Application to Image Fusion, 2011; PB.002.00004; Nercessian, Shahan C.; Panetta, Karen A.; Agaian, Sos S.
    New pixel- and region-based multiresolution image fusion algorithms are introduced in this paper using the Parameterized Logarithmic Image Processing (PLIP) model, a framework more suitable for processing images. A mathematical analysis shows that the Logarithmic Image Processing (LIP) model and standard mathematical operators are extreme cases of the PLIP model operators. Moreover, the PLIP model operators also have the ability to take on cases in between LIP and standard operators based on the visual requirements of the input images. PLIP-based multiresolution decomposition schemes are developed and thoroughly applied for image fusion as analysis and synthesis methods. The new decomposition schemes and fusion rules yield novel image fusion algorithms which are able to provide visually more pleasing fusion results. LIP-based multiresolution image fusion approaches are consequently formulated due to the generalized nature of the PLIP model. Computer simulations illustrate that the proposed image fusion algorithms using the Parameterized Logarithmic Laplacian Pyramid, Parameterized Logarithmic Discrete Wavelet Transform, and Parameterized Logarithmic Stationary Wavelet Transform outperform their respective traditional approaches by both qualitative and quantitative means. The algorithms were tested over a range of different image classes, including out-of-focus, medical, surveillance, and remote sensing images.
    Image processing; Data processing; Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering
  - A Retrospective Assessment of Occupational Exposure to Elemental Carbon in the U.S. Trucking Industry, 2011; PB.002.00005; Davis, Mary E.; Hart, Jamie E.; Laden, Francine; Garshick, Eric; Smith, Thomas J.
    Background: Despite considerable epidemiologic evidence about the health effects of chronic exposure to vehicle exhaust, efforts at defining the extent of risk have been limited by the lack of historical exposure measurements suitable for use in epidemiologic studies and for risk assessment. Objectives: We sought to reconstruct exposure to elemental carbon (EC), a marker of diesel and other vehicle exhaust exposure, in a large national cohort of U.S. trucking industry workers. Methods: We identified the predictors of measured exposures based on a statistical model and used this information to extrapolate exposures across the cohort nationally. These estimates were adjusted for changes in work-related conditions over time based on a previous exposure assessment of this industry, and for changes in background levels based on a trend analysis of historical air pollution data, to derive monthly estimates of EC exposure for each job and trucking terminal combination between 1971 and 2000. Results: Occupational exposure to EC declined substantially over time, and we found significant variability in estimated exposures both within and across job groups, trucking terminals, and regions of the United States. Average estimated EC exposures during a typical work shift ranged from < 1 ?g/m3 in the lowest exposed category in the 1990s to > 40 ?g/m3 for workers in the highest exposed jobs in the 1970s. Conclusions: Our results provide a framework for understanding changes over time in exposure to EC in the U.S. trucking industry. Our assessment should minimize exposure misclassification by capturing variation among terminals and across U.S. regions, and changes over time.
    Public Health; Trucking; Air--Pollution; Lungs Cancer; Department of Urban and Environmental Policy and Planning
  - Extracellular Heat Shock Protein (Hsp)70 and Hsp90alpha Assist in Matrix Metalloproteinase-2 Activation and Breast Cancer Cell Migration and Invasion, 2011; PB.002.00006; Sims, Jessica D.; McCready, Jessica; Jay, Daniel G.
    Breast cancer is second only to lung cancer in cancer-related deaths in women, and the majority of these deaths are caused by metastases. Obtaining a better understanding of migration and invasion, two early steps in metastasis, is critical for the development of treatments that inhibit breast cancer metastasis. In a functional proteomic screen for proteins required for invasion, extracellular heat shock protein 90 alpha (Hsp90alpha) was identified and shown to activate matrix metalloproteinase 2 (MMP-2). The mechanism of MMP-2 activation by Hsp90alpha is unknown. Intracellular Hsp90alpha commonly functions with a complex of co-chaperones, leading to our hypothesis that Hsp90alpha functions similarly outside of the cell. In this study, we show that a complex of co-chaperones outside of breast cancer cells assists Hsp90alpha mediated activation of MMP-2. We demonstrate that the co-chaperones Hsp70, Hop, Hsp40, and p23 are present outside of breast cancer cells and co-immunoprecipitate with Hsp90alpha in vitro and in breast cancer conditioned media. These co-chaperones also increase the association of Hsp90alpha and MMP-2 in vitro. This co-chaperone complex enhances Hsp90alpha-mediated activation of MMP-2 in vitro, while inhibition of Hsp70 in conditioned media reduces this activation and decreases cancer cell migration and invasion. Together, these findings support a model in which MMP-2 activation by an extracellular co-chaperone complex mediated by Hsp90alpha increases breast cancer cell migration and invasion. Our studies provide insight into a novel pathway for MMP-2 activation and suggest Hsp70 as an additional extracellular target for anti-metastatic drug development.
    Breast--Cancer; Heat shock proteins; Department of Cellular and Molecular Physiology
  - An International Evaluation of Ultrasound vs. Computed Tomography in the Diagnosis of Appendicitis, 2011; PB.002.00007; Weiner, Scott G.; Reich, Betzalel; Zalut, Todd
    Background: Abdominal computed tomography scan (CT) is the preferred radiographic study for the diagnosis of appendicitis in the United States, while radiologist-operated ultrasound (US) is often used in Israel. This comparative international study evaluates the performance of CT vs. US in the evaluation of acute appendicitis. Methods: A retrospective chart analysis was conducted at two tertiary care teaching hospitals, one in each country. Adult patients (age 18-99) with an Emergency Department (ED) working diagnosis of appendicitis between 1 January 2005 and 31 December 2006 were reviewed. Included patients had at least one imaging study, went to the OR, and had documented surgical pathology results. Results: Of 136 patients in the United States with the ED diagnosis of appendicitis, 79 met inclusion criteria for the CT cohort. Based on pathology, CT had a sensitivity of 100% (95% CI 95.4-100%). The negative appendectomy rate in patients with positive CT was 0%. Total median ED length of stay was 533 min [IQR (450-632)] and median time from CT order to completion was 184 min [IQR (147-228)]. Of 520 patients in Israel, 197 were included in the US cohort. Based on final pathology, US had a sensitivity of 68.4% (95% CI 61.2-74.8%). The negative appendectomy rate in patients with positive US was 5.5%. The median ED length of stay for these patients was 387 min [IQR (259-571.5)]. Of the patients, 23.4% had subsequent CT scans. Median time from US order to completion was 20 min [IQR (7-49)]. Both time values were p less than 0.001 when compared with CT. We furthermore calculate that a first pass approach of using US first, and then performing a confirmatory CT scan in patients with negative US, would have saved an average of 88.0 minutes per patient in the United States and avoided CT in 65% of patients. Conclusions: Radiologist-operated US had inferior sensitivity and positive predictive value when compared with CT, though was significantly faster to perform, and avoided radiation and contrast in a majority of patients. A first-pass approach using US first and then CT if US is not diagnostic may be desirable in some institutions.
    Appendicitis--Imaging; Appendicitis--diagnosis; Department of Emergency Medicine
  - Identification of Biochemical Network Modules Based on Shortest Retroactive Distances, 2011; PB.002.00008; Lee, Kyongbum; Sridharan, Gautham Vivek; Hassoun, Soha
    Modularity analysis offers a route to better understand the organization of cellular biochemical networks as well as to derive practically useful, simplified models of these complex systems. While there is general agreement regarding the qualitative properties of a biochemical module, there is no clear consensus on the quantitative criteria that may be used to systematically derive these modules. In this work, we investigate cyclical interactions as the defining characteristic of a biochemical module. We utilize a round trip distance metric, termed Shortest Retroactive Distance (ShReD), to characterize the retroactive connectivity between any two reactions in a biochemical network and to group together network components that mutually influence each other. We evaluate the metric on two types of networks that feature feedback interactions: (i) epidermal growth factor receptor (EGFR) signaling and (ii) liver metabolism supporting drug transformation. For both networks, the ShReD partitions found hierarchically arranged modules that confirm biological intuition. In addition, the partitions also revealed modules that are less intuitive. In particular, ShReD-based partition of the metabolic network identified a redox module that couples reactions of glucose, pyruvate, lipid and drug metabolism through shared production and consumption of NADPH. Our results suggest that retroactive interactions arising from feedback loops and metabolic cycles significantly contribute to the modularity of biochemical networks. For metabolic networks, cofactors play an important role as allosteric effectors that mediate the retroactive interactions.
    Computational biology; Department of Chemical and Biological Engineering
  - Contact Printing of Colloidal Nanocrystal Thin Films for Hybrid Organic/Quantum Dot Optoelectronic Devices, 2011; PB.002.00009; Panzer, Matthew J.; Aidala, Katherine; Bulovic, Vladimir
    Novel thin film optoelectronic devices containing both inorganic colloidal semiconductor quantum dots (QDs) and organic semiconductor thin films have been widely investigated in recent years for a variety of applications. Here, we review one of the most versatile and successful methods developed to integrate these two dissimilar material classes into a functional multilayered device: contact printing of colloidal QD films. Experimental details regarding the contact printing process are outlined, and the key advantages of this QD deposition method over other commonly encountered techniques are discussed. The use of tapping mode atomic force microscopy (AFM) to effectively characterize QD film morphology both on an elastomeric stamp (before contact printing) and as-transferred to the organic semiconductor receiving film (after contact printing) is also described. Finally, we offer suggestions for future efforts directed toward the goal of rapid, continuous QD deposition over larger substrates for the advancement of hybrid optoelectronic thin film devices.
    Department of Chemical and Biological Engineering
  - Overcoming natural replication barriers: differential helicase requirements, 2011; PB.002.00010; Freudenreich, Catherine H.; Anand, Ranjith P.; Shah, Kartik A.; Niu, Hengyao; Sung, Patrick; Mirkin, Sergei M.